<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOME on Mart Jürisoo</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HOME on Mart Jürisoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Mart Jürisoo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Survivor Filming and Airing Schedule</title>
      <link>/post/survivor-filming-and-airing-schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/survivor-filming-and-airing-schedule/</guid>
      <description>This is a visualisation I made. It&#39;s really true.
 (Click for bigger)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Dallas Mavericks Have The Best Offense Ever?</title>
      <link>/post/does-dallas-mavericks-have-the-best-offense-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/does-dallas-mavericks-have-the-best-offense-ever/</guid>
      <description>Before the NBA season was shut down, there was a lot of talk of Dallas Mavericks having the best offense in the NBA history. On its surface, it seems true - 116.7 is the highest offensive rating (the estimated number of points a team will score in 100 possessions) any NBA team has ever had. However, the context in which the number has been achieved matters too. Here&#39;s a chart of the league average offensive (and defensive) ratings:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Survivor Episode Rating on IMDb</title>
      <link>/post/every-survivor-episode-rating-on-imdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/every-survivor-episode-rating-on-imdb/</guid>
      <description>My lockdown binging show of choice has been Survivor. With 39 completed seasons, watching all of them is unlikely so I turned to trusty IMDb to see which are the good ones. So here are all the Survivor episode ratings visualised with a hard to read but thematic font.
 (Click for bigger)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Outlying Scoring Performances in NBA History</title>
      <link>/post/most-outlying-scoring-performances-in-nba-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/most-outlying-scoring-performances-in-nba-history/</guid>
      <description>Shake Milton scoring 39 points yesterday was quite an outlier from his career average of 6.2. In fact, it was such an outlier, it made me wonder if it&#39;s the biggest outlier ever.
Spoiler: it wasn&#39;t.
The biggest outlier ever measured in standard deviations from the players&amp;rsquo; career average was, in fact, Mario West scoring 13 while averaging 0.9 points per game.
Here&#39;s the all-time top 50:
   player_name matchup game_date career_ppg sd pts deviations     Mario West NJN @ PHI 2011-04-01 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rock paper scissors in the UFC</title>
      <link>/post/rock-paper-scissors-in-the-ufc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rock-paper-scissors-in-the-ufc/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday fella by the name of Dan Hooker beat Paul Felder in a UFC fight. Last September, Felder had beat Edson Barboza who in 2018 beat the aforementioned Dan Hooker. That, my friends, is a rock paper scissors situation.
Counting only fights in the UFC, three fighters have wins over each other in such a way 237 times. There would be hundreds more if we were to include other fight promotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game-Winning Buzzer-Beaters in the NBA</title>
      <link>/post/game-winning-buzzer-beaters-in-the-nba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/game-winning-buzzer-beaters-in-the-nba/</guid>
      <description>Basketball-reference just released a dataset of every NBA game-winning buzzer-beater ever. Let&#39;s take a closer look, then.
A total of 772 shots. Here&#39;s the season-by-season distribution: 
On average you would expect there to be 16.5 game-winning buzzer-beater in a 30-team 82-game season. This year&#39;s 5 is way behind the pace.
Most of the shots have been at the rim: 
The players to make at least five are as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UFC Rankings Website</title>
      <link>/portfolio/ufc-rankings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/ufc-rankings/</guid>
      <description>This was a page that visualized and summarized the individual rankings that make up the overall UFC rankings. The aim of it was to shine a light on possibly weird decisions by the rankers.
Since the creation of the page the UFC has hidden the individual rankings and only show the overall rankings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Over and Underachieving Countries in European Soccer</title>
      <link>/post/over-and-underachieving-countries-in-european-soccer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/over-and-underachieving-countries-in-european-soccer/</guid>
      <description>An interesting thing to look at, I thought, was to see how international football teams perform when measured against how they would be expected to perform based on the nations&amp;rsquo; demographic, economic, climatic, and cultural variables.
First, here is how the teams are rated based on the average score of the past 15 months in FIFA Rankings:
 (blue is better, red is worse)
Now, no surprises there - generally, the big countries in the West are strong, the smaller ones in the East are weak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NBA Players Who Play Every Game</title>
      <link>/post/nba-players-who-play-every-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nba-players-who-play-every-game/</guid>
      <description>On a recent New York Knicks broadcast, the commentators lamented the fact that only 21 players played in all 82 regular season games last year. The implication being that it&#39;s not that many. But, how does it compare historically?
So, he was right - there is a downwards trend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing NBA player and fan votes for the All-Star game</title>
      <link>/post/comparing-nba-player-and-fan-votes-for-the-all-star-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/comparing-nba-player-and-fan-votes-for-the-all-star-game/</guid>
      <description>The NBA released the All-Star starter voting results this past week. Part of the formula for deciding the All-Stars are player and fan votes. I thought it&#39;d be interesting to see where the two groups vote differently. (Media members also vote but since there are comparatively so few of them, I&#39;ll be ignoring them for now.)
After normalizing the player and fan votes, we get the following chart: Technically, I could just compare the player and fan vote ranks, however, that would leave a lot of information off the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning a Debate at The Soho Forum</title>
      <link>/post/winning-a-debate-at-the-soho-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/winning-a-debate-at-the-soho-forum/</guid>
      <description>The Soho Forum is an Oxford-style debate series that takes place in NYC. So far there have been 39 debates(and one &amp;ldquo;discussion&amp;rdquo;).
Oxford-style means that the audience is polled on the resolution before and after the debate and the winner is decided by comparing the two polls. At The Soho Forum, the person increasing their vote percentage point more is considered the winner. Though there are alternative ways to score an Oxford-style debate, which I will be looking at at a later date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding The Challenge GOAT: Eliminations</title>
      <link>/post/finding-the-challenge-goat-eliminations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/finding-the-challenge-goat-eliminations/</guid>
      <description>What&#39;s better than America&#39;s fourth favorite sport - Real World/Road Rules Challenge? Not many things I can think of.
To start the search for the True Statistical Challenge GOAT, looking at the elimination challenges is a good(easy) place to go. While not the be-all and end-all, they are straightforward one-on-one(usually) competitions unlike many daily and final challenges. Ignoring social and political games, these are mostly a measure of physical skill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Points Scored in the NBA by Minutes Played</title>
      <link>/post/most-points-scored-in-the-nba-by-minutes-played/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/most-points-scored-in-the-nba-by-minutes-played/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago Giannis Antetokounmpo scored 37 points in 21 minutes against the New York Knicks. That made me really wonder if that&#39;s the most points anyone&#39;s ever scored in the NBA in 21 minutes. Well, turns out, it isn&#39;t. The most anyone ever scored in 21 minutes was Quintin Dailey	who scored 38 points in 1986.
And here is a hard to read visualization of the top scorers at each minute played since the 1983-84 season:  (Click for bigger)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter Book Bot</title>
      <link>/portfolio/bastiat-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/bastiat-bot/</guid>
      <description>@TheLawByBastiat is a Twitter bot that tweets out the book The Law by Frédéric Bastiat one sentance at a time.
It will take roughly 2 years to finish the whole book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scott Horton Show Episode Finder</title>
      <link>/portfolio/scott-horton/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/scott-horton/</guid>
      <description>The Scott Horton Show is the world&#39;s finest anti-war podcast/radio show that&#39;s been airing since 1999.
Now at over 5,000 episodes, this webpage was created to help finding episodes by guest and/or the topic.
In 2020, God willing, I will remake the page in JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing RAPTOR and RPM</title>
      <link>/post/comparing-raptor-and-rpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/comparing-raptor-and-rpm/</guid>
      <description>When fivethirtyeight.com launched their new all-in-one NBA player ratings before the 2019-20 season, it was very exciting, very exciting indeed. That rating is called RAPTOR.
We can only guess how it&#39;s made or what it means but it does offer an alternative to ESPN&#39;s Real Plus-Minus, which some consider to be the best all-in-one rating. It&#39;s impossible to say which one is more &amp;ldquo;accurate&amp;rdquo; (it isn&#39;t but I shan&#39;t be doing it today) but we can compare the two rating systems in how their evaluations of players differ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking The UFC PPV Sales</title>
      <link>/post/tracking-the-ufc-ppv-sales/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tracking-the-ufc-ppv-sales/</guid>
      <description>(Click for bigger)
With UFC moving their pay-per-view events exclusively behind ESPN&#39;s paywall in 2019 and thus ending any access to accurate sales numbers, it&#39;d be a fitting time to look back at the numbers for the whole run.
The biggest PPV events are highlighted by text and color-grouped by the star fighter: Conor McGregor, Ronda Rousey, Brock Lesnar, Georges St. Pierre, and Jon Jones.
The vertical dotted line marks the sell of UFC to WMG-IMG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy Basketball Correlation Matrix</title>
      <link>/post/fantasy-basketball-correlation-matrix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fantasy-basketball-correlation-matrix/</guid>
      <description>The matrix is based on the 2019-20 NBA season&#39;s per-game standard scores of the top 200 players.
This could be used as a guide for possible punting strategies. There are many players with non-standard statistical contributions, however it might be a good idea to keep within standard lines to have the biggest potential player-base and to minimize categorical waste.
The players can be divided into 3 main groups:
 ft-fg3m-pts-ast-stl blk-reb-fg tov  Based on actual basketball roles, the first two groups are smalls and bigs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Football Results Database</title>
      <link>/portfolio/fantasy-league-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/fantasy-league-website/</guid>
      <description>This is a database of every international football result ever. Or quite close to that. I created it before the 2018 World Cup when I couldn&#39;t find a simply formatted results database.
Most of the results were scraped from two websites that don&#39;t exist anymore. Technically, obviously, all the results are out there. Just not in a neat file. But now they are. And they&#39;re updated monthly.
It is one of the most popular datasets on Kaggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy League History Website</title>
      <link>/portfolio/kaggle-football/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 19:47:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/kaggle-football/</guid>
      <description>This is a website tracking the NBA fantasy league I&#39;ve played in since 2006. The main reason for its creation was that most of the websites hosting fantasy games do not keep the leagues&amp;rsquo; histories.
By now the website is does not only keep the historic records but displays all kinds of statistics of league, which has added greatly to the enjoyment of the game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>